A Finding Aid to the Lillian and Frederick Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-2003, bulk 1958-2000, in the Archives of American Art AAA.kieslill
Archives of American Art
- Frederick Kiesler papers, 1923-1992; Series 2; 7.1 Linear feet Boxes 40-46, OV 53
  - Business and Financial Records, 1937-1965; 2.3
    - Ford Foundation Special Account, 1963-1964 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Foreign Travel, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Job Applicants, 1956-1959 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Job Applicants, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Kiesler and Bartos Finances, 1957, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Leases, 1937-1965 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Tax Return Records 1941, 1941-1942 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Tax Return Records 1942, 1942-1944 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Tax Return Records 1943, 1943-1944 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Tax Return Records 1944, 1944-1945 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Tax Return Records 1945, 1945-1946 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Tax Return Records 1946, 1947 (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Tax Return Records 1948, 1948-1949 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Tax Return Records 1949, 1949-1950 (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - Tax Return Records 1950 (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - Tax Return Records 1951, 1951-1952 (Box 43, Folder 24)
    - Tax Return Records 1952, 1952-1953 (Box 43, Folder 25)
    - Tax Return Records 1953, 1953-1954 (Box 43, Folder 26)
    - Tax Return Records, 1953-1954 (Box 43, Folder 27-30)
    - Tax Return Records 1959, 1958-1960 (Box 43, Folder 31-32)
    - Tax Return Records 1959, 1958-1960 (Box 44, Folder 1-6)
    - Tax Return Records 1960, 1959-1961 (Box 44, Folder 7-13)
    - Tax Return Records 1961, 1960-1961 (Box 44, Folder 14-15)
    - Tax Return Records 1961, 1960-1961 (Box 45, Folder 1-4)
    - Tax Return Records 1963 (Box 45, Folder 5-8)
  - Exhibition Files, 1924-1992, undated; 2.4
    Exhibition files contain correspondence and printed material related to exhibits held primarily after Frederick Kiesler's death. Additional material related to exhibits can be found in Papers Related to Frederick Kiesler, 1913-2003 (Subseries 1.10) in the Lillian Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-2003 (Series 1). Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - The Book of the Shrine, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Inside the Endless House, 1966-1969, undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - International Theatre Exposition (in German), 1924 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1965-1966 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Monograph, Bogner, Dieter. Friedrich Kiesler 1890-1965. Vienna: Löcker Verlag, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Monograph, Phillips, Lisa. Frederick Kiesler. New York: Whitney Museum of American Art, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - "The Object in the Open Air," Museum of Contemporary Crafts, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - The Book of the Shrine, 1992 (Box OV 53)
      Oversized material from Box 45, Folder 9.
  - Teaching Files, 1937-1964, undated; 2.5
    Found here is correspondence, artwork and papers by Frederick Kiesler's students at Juilliard, notes on productions, and administrative files. Correspondence regarding teaching can also be found in Correspondence, 1923-1965, undated (Subseries 2.2) in the Frederick Kiesler Papers, 1923-1992 (Series 2). Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Contracts, 1937-1940 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Juilliard Students' Works, undated (Box 45, Folder 17-18)
    - Juilliard Students' Works, Papers, 1944, 1954-1956, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Juilliard Students' Works, Visual Arts (3 folders), 1955-1956, undated (Box 46, Folder 2-4)
    - Juilliard Miscellaneous, 1939-1956, undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - State Education Department (N.Y.), 1940-1964, undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Writings and Notes, 1933-1980, undated; 2.6
    Writings and notes contains Lillian Kiesler's "Bibliography of Writings By or About Frederick Kiesler" (1971; 1980), as well as desk notes, a notebook, and research material. Addition writings can be found in Papers Related to Frederick Kiesler, 1913-2003 (Subseries 1.10) in the Lillian Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-2003 (Series 1). Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Bibliography of Writings By or About Frederick Kiesler, 1971, undated (Box 46, Folder 7-8)
    - Bibliography of Writings By or About Frederick Kiesler, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 9-11)
    - Desk Notes and Miscellany, 1959 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Desk Notes and Miscellany, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, 1933-1965, undated (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Research Material Notes for "Architectural Record", 1937 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Printed Material, 1926-1966, undated; 2.7
    Printed material includes newspaper and magazine clippings, announcements and invitations, flyers, and plastic samples. Additional related printed material can be found in Papers Related to Frederick Kiesler, 1913-2003 (Subseries 1.10) in the Lillian Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-2003 (Series 1). The items are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Clippings, 1926-1966 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939-1965 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Printers on Plastic, undated (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Clippings, 1962 (Box OV 53)
      Oversized clippings from Box 46, Folder 16.
  - Photographic Material, undated; 2.8
    There is one folder of black and white photographs of sculptures. Each photograph is notated on the back in pencil. Additional related material can be found in Papers Related to Frederick Kiesler, 1913-2003 (Subseries 1.10) and Photographic Material, circa 1910s-1950s (Subseries 1.13) in the Lillian Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-200 (Series 1).
    - Photographic Material, undated (Box 46, Folder 19)